{
    "id": "bd538fc2593f4a84904bcd9940b73feb",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The dog wagged ……………………… tail.",
            "description": "It's means it is or it has.",
            "answers": [
                "it's",
                "its"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4f175815915e4aba8ea3c459c08b4501"
        },
        {
            "question": "It is time you ……………………. your hair.",
            "description": "After it’s time, a past tense is used with a present meaning.",
            "answers": [
                "trim",
                "trimmed",
                "have trimmed"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1cfa001b91f249d2bd085363cc1c85e6"
        },
        {
            "question": "The farmer has a hen that ………………………. golden eggs.",
            "description": "To lay is to put something down flat.",
            "answers": [
                "lies",
                "lays",
                "lains"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "cb4d82c3e67b40feb99f71ffd2822060"
        },
        {
            "question": "She does ………………………. work than I do and yet she earns more.",
            "description": "Use less with uncountable nouns and fewer with plural nouns.",
            "answers": [
                "less",
                "fewer",
                "lesser"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "8e791073a72b415c9a6b6be3afaaeb28"
        },
        {
            "question": "His composition won the first prize because it had the ………………………… mistakes.",
            "description": "Use the superlative form after the. Fewest is used with plural nouns and least is used with uncountable nouns. ",
            "answers": [
                "least",
                "fewest",
                "fewer",
                "less"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "7616c37d9a984ae98d9a2f87de541e2f"
        },
        {
            "question": "You look  ……………………",
            "description": "Look is a copular verb. We use an adjective to modify copular verbs. ",
            "answers": [
                "happy",
                "happily"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "8574637d9ee84b2e836a882a9aac71bf"
        },
        {
            "question": "I can’t make him ……………………. his mind.",
            "description": "Make is followed by object + infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "change",
                "to change",
                "changing"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "5147752b0dae42f48e640eb0c1ebccba"
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t speak English very well but I can make myself ……………………….",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "understand",
                "understood"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "520f0c0d755e433ebb5db063f4ae79ce"
        },
        {
            "question": "She will not ………………………. this.",
            "description": "The infinitive is used without to after modals.",
            "answers": [
                "permit",
                "to permit"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "da140b31f14e4c718a4fd48760e468e5"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ……………………….. to her for twenty years.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "is married",
                "has been married",
                "has married"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "75b1a36636a24a629d1459f3bc6fe5da"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………… you are right.",
            "description": "Perhaps is similar to maybe. ",
            "answers": [
                "Maybe",
                "May be",
                "Perhaps"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "e6fb5f03717d4489b3aec4d60b785d90"
        },
        {
            "question": "Would you mind ............................. me with the homework?",
            "description": "We use ing forms or if-clauses after do you mind…? and would you mind….?\r\n\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "to help",
                "helping"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "45bdf42c0b304a8d9e393fa6c5613a34"
        }
    ]
}